

PROFILE

UI/UX designer and front end developer with 10 years of experience in digital agencies and corporates.

Skilled about digital products development with user-friendly interfaces. Able to manage complex projects from early stages (analysis, sitemap, user personas, wireframes, low/high fidelity prototypes) till their online release (final visuals, assets and styleguides creation, front-end coding, testing and deployment).

I'm used to focus on data analysis and graphic details to ensure an engaging and unique digital experience, in order to value contents and to increase brand awareness, online sells and lead generations.

FORMATION

Javascript training course Udemy

Online
June 2021 - November 2021

PHP and MySQL training course M.A.C Formazione

Ancona, Italy March 2021 - May 2021

University of Rome "La Sapienza" First level degree in Industrial Design on Graphic and Multimedia Communication Area at First Faculty of Architecture "L.Quaroni"

Rome, Italy September 2008 - December 2011

Liceo scientifico "G. Galieli" High school leaving qualifications

Macerata, Italy September 2003 - July 2008

TOOLS

Miro / Adobe Creative Suite / Figma / Sketch / UX Pin / Html5 / Tailwind / Css3 / Sass-Scss / Javascript / jQuery / Vue JS / Nuxt JS / PHP / MySQL / Magento / Shopify / WooCommerce / Bootstrap / Wordpress /

Mauro Micozzi

UX UI Designer Front End Developer

www.behance.net/maumicozzi3075mau.micozzi@gmail.com

+34 634 215222

EXPERIENCE

UX UI Designer - Front End Dev Freelance

Macerata, Italy London, UK Tenerife, Canary Island January 2022 - NOW

- Understanding clients' needs to support them by providing online strategy to increase brand awareness, sells and lead generations
- Data analysis, sitemap creation with development of wireframe and low/high quality prototypes till the development of the final UI
- Creation of logos, websites, e-commerce, email/newsletter templates, mobile applications and assets for social media and adv
- Maintenance and optimization through data analysis and reports

Co-Founder & UX UI Designer ShopStarter▶

www.shop-starter.com

Macerata, Italy September 2019 - December 2021

- Supporting small/medium size company to enter the online market and start selling their products or services
- Elaboration of selling strategy with relatives supports like landing pages, e-commerce website, lead generations funnel and email marketing automations
- Data analysis and reports of insights to improve the strategy according to data (CTR, bounce rate, conversion rate and CLV)

Co-Founder & UX UI Designer monopattinoelettrico.info

www.monopattinoelettrico.info

Macerata, Italy Novemebr 2019 - December 2021

- Creation of blog website and implementation of on page SEO strategy to improve ranking on Google
- Managing and supervising external copywriter productions
- Elaboration of B2C and B2B strategy to connect people who need technical assistance to mechanics all over Italy
- Managing partnership with external providers to improve the quality of services for the community

Technical Director

www.famiglia-adesiva.com

Rome, Macerata, Italy May 2018 - Decemebr 2021

- Branding and stickers colletion design (more than 350 stickers)
- UX UI creation for the e-commerce website (Magento, Shopify)
- Mananging external providers for the stickers production and improving the process with automatic creation of the files for printing
- Creation of social media and digital adv assets (FB, IG)
- Creation and set up of email marketing automations and newsletter
- Managing partnership with other business related professionals

Web & Graphic Designer

THE NIDO COLLECTION

www.nidoliving.com

London, UK August 2017 - April 2018

- Responsible for the overall customer's experience on the website
- Creation of graphic assets for marketing materials and social media
 Support the development of the Nido App with external provider
- Creation of brand materials (brochures, residence logo's, business)
- cards, branded office materials, giveaways and onsite signage)
- Supporting marketing team with new visual strategies and providing them new tools for analysis and for tracking user activities

UX UI Designer

TANGENT

www.tangent.co.uk

London, UK September 2016 - July 2017

- Analysis and elaboration of sitemaps, user personas and user journeys to solve users problem and focus on important details
- Design of complex digital UI for website, e-commerce, web app and mobile application
- Creation and maintenance of design systems
- Supporting project managers to deliver dependencies and managing client expectations

Mobile Design Manager POKER STARS

www.pokerstars.com

London, UK January 2016 - August 2016

- Creation of Buzz section for all the three verticals of the company (Poker, Casino and Bet) and elaborate new visual strategies
- Optimize all productions for desktop and mobile devices
- Creation of bespoke screenshots to optimize performance of PS apps for all verticals
- Managing external providers productions, assigning web projects and supervising the development

Web Designer

Go Project

www.goproject.it

Rome, Italy July 2014 - June 2015

Web Designer



www.gag.it

Rome, Italy March 2014 - June 2014

Art Director Art Attack Native Advertising

www.welcometothearkage.com

Rome, Italy July 2012 - March 2014